SHEREZADE MAQUEDA

PROFESSIONAL CHEF

CONTACT

+34689392447

mlsherezade@gmail.com

Reference: Bobbi Steele info@bobbisteele.com

SKILLS

Communication

Empathy and sociability

Problem solving ability

Team work

Change adaptable

EDUCATION

Lic in Audiovisual Communication

Universidad Complutense

2007 - 2013

Chef

Culinary School G11 Hamburg

2015 - 2018

UX Design

Career Foundry

2022 - current

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English



German



PROFILE

I'm a professional chef with over 8 years of experience in high-end restaurants across Germany. During this time, I not only was leading my section of the kitchen, but I also joined a part-time job as a contract chef, which allowed me to work in different kitchens on a regular basis. This experience allowed me to become more flexible and adaptable to the people around me in high stress environments.

I am currently looking to take my experience and use it to join an operations team in a customer-facing role in a new industry outside of gastronomy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sous Chef

Lobe Block 2022 - current

- · Kitchen management and coordination
- Menu development, design and implementation
- Budget management for the kitchen, events and catering
- Communication with vendors, guests and clients
- Teach junior chefs the ins and outs of following defined recipes and how to add their own twist to traditional dishes
- Responsible for budgeting, cash flow maintenance and maintaining sustainable profit levels

Lead Chef

2020 - 2022 Side by Side

- · Prepared, cooked and served food while maintaining high quality standards for food preparation and presentation.
- Upheld company procedures and executed daily and weekly procedures, including temperature checks, food labelling, dating and storage.
- Assisted with acceptance and storage of deliveries
- · Reconciled inventories received with purchase orders and reported damaged goods or discrepancies.
- Created and maintained safe working environment in accordance with OSHA standards, company policies and regulatory requirements
- Removed hazards and identified equipment malfunctions.

Chef de Partie

Le Meridien Hotel Hamburg

2015 - 2020

- Responsible for training, developing and motivating culinary staff and kitchen supervisors to meet food preparation and serving standards
- Direct day-to-day operations in the kitchen and also dining areas
- Provide guidance and direction to restaurant workers, including setting performance standards and monitoring performance.
- Accountable for developing and testing menu items as well as the pricing of all menu items

English Teacher

Calanda Academy

- Structure, design and implement the teaching curriculum from B1 courses to C2
- Administrative responsibility such as fill invoices, organise tuition fees and front desk duties.
- Communication and marketing associate duties.